galacticconnection.com 2019-12-17

# Privacy Policy | Galactic Connection

Please read this Privacy Policy carefully. By visiting and using the site, you agree that your use of our site and any dispute over privacy is governed by this Privacy Policy. Because the web is an evolving medium, we may update this Privacy Policy at any time, by posting the amended version on this site including the effective date of the updated version. We will announce any material changes to this Privacy Policy through an alert on our website and/or via email. By continuing to use the site after we post any such changes, you accept the Privacy Policy as modified.

This Privacy Policy discloses the privacy practices for GalacticConnection.com. This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by this website. It will notify you of the following:

  1. What personally identifiable information is collected from you through the website, how it is used and with whom it may be shared.
  2. What choices are available to you regarding the use of your data.
  3. The security procedures in place to protect the misuse of your information.
  4. How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information.

### INFORMATION COLLECTION, USE, AND SHARING

  * We are the sole owners of the information collected on this site. We only have access to/collect information that you voluntarily give us via newsletter sign-up, purchase, email or other direct contact from you.
  * Your information will never be sold, reused, rented, disclosed, or loaned to any other party, company, or agency (unless in connection with legal requirements).
  * We will use your information to respond to you regarding the reason you contacted us. We will not share your information with any third party outside of our organization, other than as necessary to fulfil your request, e.g. to ship an order.
  * Unless you ask us not to, we may contact you via email to tell you about specials, new products or services, or changes to this privacy policy.

### YOUR ACCESS TO AND CONTROL OVER INFORMATION

You can do the following at any time by contacting us at admin@galacticconnection.com

  * See what data we have about you, if any.
  * Change/correct any data we have about you.
  * Have us delete any data we have about you.
  * Express any concern you have about our use of your data.
  * May opt out of any future contacts from us.

### PERSONAL DATA

#### Newsletter Subscribers

We collect your email address and first name when you voluntarily provide it to us when you sign up for our newsletter. This is done via a hosted sign up form from the technology provider we use for newsletter mailings, namely MailChimp, and subscriber database is securely kept on their servers. Please refer to Mailchimp for their own [Privacy Policy](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/) and [Terms](https://mailchimp.com/legal/).

If you sign up for our newsletter, you will receive daily newsletter emails, and on rare occasion special updates or news regarding the website or other products or services that we believe may be of interest to you.

You may opt out of such email communications at any time by clicking the “unsubscribe” button found at the bottom of each email.

#### Purchasers

When you order any products or services from our website the payments are done through third party payment processors, like Paypal. If shipping of products is required we collect your name, email and shipping address for such purposes. If necessary we may communicate with you via email concerning your order.

We have no access to and do not collect or store your payment card details. That information is provided directly to our third-party payment processors whose use of your personal information is governed by their Privacy Policy. These payment processors adhere to the standards set by PCI-DSS as managed by the PCI Security Standards Council, which is a joint effort of brands like Visa, Mastercard, American Express and Discover. PCI-DSS requirements help ensure the secure handling of payment information.

### DATA PROTECTION RIGHTS UNDER GENERAL DATA PROTECTION REGULATION (GDPR)

If you are a resident of the European Economic Area (EEA), you have certain data protection rights:

  * the right to be informed
  * the right of access
  * the right to rectification
  * the right to erasure
  * the right to restrict processing
  * the right to data portability
  * the right to object
  * the right not to be subject to automated decision-making including profiling

Please note that we may ask you to verify your identity before responding to such requests.

If you believe that our processing of your personal information infringes data protection laws, you have a legal right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority responsible for data protection. For more information, please contact your local data protection authority in the European Economic Area (EEA).

If you wish to be informed what Personal Data we hold about you and if you want it to be amended or removed from our systems, please contact us.

### COOKIES

When you visit our website we may send one or more cookies – a small text file containing a string of alphanumeric characters – to your computer that uniquely identifies your browser and allows enhanced navigation through the site. A cookie may also convey information to us about how you use our website (e.g. the pages you view, the links you click and other actions you take), and allows us to track your visits to our website over time.

A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive after you close your browser. Persistent cookies may be used by your browser on subsequent visits to the site. Persistent cookies can be removed by following your web browser’s directions. A session cookie is temporary and disappears after you close your browser.

Most browsers allow you to refuse to accept cookies and to delete cookies. However, some features of the website may not function properly if the ability to accept cookies is disabled. The methods for doing so vary from browser to browser, and from version to version. You can however obtain up-to-date information about blocking and deleting cookies via these links:

(a) <https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en> (Chrome);

(b) <https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences> (Firefox);

(c) <http://www.opera.com/help/tutorials/security/cookies/> (Opera);

(d) <https://support.microsoft.com/en-gb/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies> (Internet Explorer);

(e) <https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21411> (Safari); and

(f) <https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-10-microsoft-edge-and-privacy> (Edge).

The site also includes links to other websites and provides access to products and services offered by third parties, whose privacy policies we do not control. When you access another website or purchase third-party products or services through the site, use of any information you provide is governed by the privacy policy of the operator of the site you are visiting or the provider of such products or services.

#### Google Analytics

We use Google Analytics, a web analytics service offered by Google that tracks and reports website traffic. Google Analytics gathers information about website use by means of cookies. The information gathered relating to our website is used to create reports about the use of our website. Google’s privacy policy is available at: <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>

You can opt-out of having made your activity on the site available to Google Analytics by installing the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on. The add-on prevents the Google Analytics JavaScript (ga.js, analytics.js, and dc.js) from sharing information with Google Analytics about visits activity.

 **If you feel that we are not abiding by this privacy policy, you should contact us immediately by sending an email to admin@galacticconnection.com**

 _Effective 25 May 2018_
